Sahajayoga and essential medicine
霎哈嘉瑜伽和基本医药
Shri Mataji Nirmaladevi- grandmother, scholar and freedom fighter.
锡吕.玛塔吉.涅玛拉.戴维 ---  一位祖母，学者和自由战士。
As a child she lived in Gandhiji’s ashram, as a student she studied medicine
她小时候曾入住圣雄甘地的静室; 学生时期研读了医学课程，
and as cry for freedom swept India she fought for her nation’s independence.
而当自由运动席卷印度时，她为国家独立而战。
The year 1970 was about her most important role.
1970年是她起着至为重要作用的一年。
The discovery of development of sahajayoga, a movement which is now spreading in worldwide.
这一年霎哈嘉瑜伽得以启迪和发展，现今已传遍世界各地。
Sahajayoga is a science of integration which results
霎哈嘉瑜伽是一门整合科学，
in man’s mental, physical and spiritual wellbeing.
带给人们精神，身体和灵性的安康。
The union of mind heart and spirit is a achieve through the working
通过我们每个人体内一个精微能量系统的运作，
of a subtle energy system within each one of us.
可以实现我们身心灵的统一和谐。
“That you are not this body, this mind, these conditionings, this ego but we are the spirit.
"你们不是这个身体，这个思维，这个制约，这个自我，我们是灵。
You don’t have to accept what I am saying blindly because blind faith leads to fanaticism.
你们不必盲目接受我所说的，因为盲目的信仰导致狂热。
But as scientist you must keep your mind open and see for
但是作为科学家，你们必须保持头脑开放，
yourself what I am saying if it is so honestly you must accept it.”
你要自己去证实我所说的，如果是真实的，你们必须诚实地接受它。"
In today’s society this subtle energy system which has its origins in very
在当今的社会，这个作为我们存在根基的精微能量系统
roots of our being has been neglected.
已经被人们忽略了。
It is out of balance.
它失去了平衡。
Today’s physical and psychological diseases are gross expressions of a subtle system in
当今出现的身心疾病正是这精微能量系统迫切需要被修复和给予滋养的
dire need of repair and nourishment.
严重诉求。
Our collective desire of a peace and rejuvenation
我们对平安和复苏的共同
is a yearning coming from deep within.
愿望源自内在深处的渴求。
It is a reflection of our internal condition.
它是我们内在状况的反映。
“We know so much though science about our civilization our advancement .
我们通过科学对文明和进步了解了很多。
This is a advancement of a tree which has grown outside very much but if we do not
这是一颗树的成长，外在已长得枝繁叶盛，
know our roots we will be destroyed.
但如果不了解我们的根，我们还是会被毁掉。
So it is important to know about our roots.
所以要了解我们的根，这很重要。
"Within each individual the subtle energy system or subtle body is divided into 3 channels
每个人体内的精微能量系统或者精微身体被分为
right, left and centre.
右，左和中间3条经脉。
The right side channel corresponds to right sympathetic chain
右脉对应自动神经系统的
of the autonomic nervous system and left hemisphere of the brain.
右交感神经系统和大脑的左半球。
While the left side connects to the right hemisphere of the brain
而左脉连接大脑的右半球
and corresponds to the left sympathetic chain.
并对应左交感神经系统。
If a person suffers a stroke in the right lobe of the brain
如果一个人右脑中风，
it is commonly known that the left side of the body becomes effective.
作为常识，他左边的身体就会受到影响。
In line with the opinion of the psychologist sahajayoga
与心理学家的观点一致，霎哈嘉瑜伽
identifies the right hemisphere of the brain has
认为右脑负责
been responsible for the functions of the lateral,
文字、艺术和表达性思维的功能。
artistic, expressive thinking. Those functions traditionally believed
一般认为，这些功能
to be more predominant in a females. The left hemisphere corresponds
女性会更有优势。
to functions of the linear, computational and mathematical logic
左脑对应着线性的，计算和数学逻辑功能，
traditionally considered to be predominant brain activity in males.
这些一般认为是男性占优势的大脑活动。
Dr. Carl Gustakh Jung well known analytical psychologist
著名的分析心理学家卡尔?古斯塔夫? 荣格博士
identifies the left and right side as the anama and anami
认为左右两脉分别具有(男性的)女性特征(anima)和(女性的)男性特征(animus)，
with the collective unconscious lying in the central channel.
集体无意识则位于中脉。
Through he studies he observe that in the every women
通过研究，他发现每个女性的内在
there is a masculine aspect within her psyche the architect of the animus and
有男性特征的一面（animus），
for every men the feminine counterpart the anima.
对于男性而言，则有对应的女性特征 (anima)。
Jung was always aware of the imbalance in western culture in favour of the masculine
荣格一直意识到西方文化由于过于推崇男性占优势的
seen in a preference for logic, analysis and external achievement.
逻辑、分析和外在成就方面而形成了不平衡。
These are all claims for mascular side or right
这些被认为是男性方面，
side of the psyche within all human beings.
在人类内在的右侧。
A right side channel also provides the energy needed for plan, act, analyze and predict.
右脉也为计划，行动，分析和预测活动提供所需能量。
On the physical level it corresponds to liver and pancreas.
在身体层面它对应肝脏和胰腺。
“This power of action moves on the right side of the spinal cord
这个行动的力量沿着脊椎的右侧上升
and coming to the optic chiasma it crosses over;
在视神经交叉处穿过
passes to the left side and creates an institution called ego.
至左侧，在这里产生一个叫自我的东西。
The institution of ego is a myth.
自我是个幻相。
What we do is to get something dead like some trees dead so make some platform
我们所做的只是制造些无生命的物品，例如一些树木死了，把它们做成一些平台
or some furniture, we take some stones and make a hall
或者家具。我们用一些石头，修建成一个厅堂，
and we think we have done a great job.
就认为自己完成了一项伟大工作。
Actually what we have done is to reconstructed the dead.
实际上，我们所做的只是重建无生命的东西。
But while doing it we get the feeling
但是当做这事情的时候，我们觉得
that we have done it something.
自己做了些了不起的事情。
That is how our ego develops.
这就是自我是怎样发展出来的。
This channel on the right hand side caters to your future.
右脉对应着未来。
So those people who plan too much think too much exhaust the energy of this centre
所以 计划过多、思考过多的人们耗尽了这个中心的能量，
because this centre has the first responsibility
因为这个中心的首要责任
to convert the fat cells in the stomach for the use of the brain
是将腹部的脂肪细胞转化为
which is overused to make them into gray cells.
过度使用的大脑所需的灰质细胞。
So when you start thinking too much it has to work more for this very important function.
因而，当你思考过多时，它不得不为这个十分重要的功能做更多的工作。
When it starts working for one function the other functions are neglected
当它开始为一个功能工作时，其他的功能便被忽略了，
and the other functions are it has to cater,
其他功能如，
to nourish or to give energy to your liver, to your pancreas, to your spleen,
照顾滋养并提供能量给肝脏、胰腺、脾脏、
to your kidneys and part of your intestine.”
肾脏和部分肠脏。
Western medicine has followed the path of right side
西方医学走的是右侧路线，
pulling a part dissecting or analyzing
只进行局部分析研究，
with little regard for the whole working mechanism of the human being.
而不综观整体的身体运作机能。
“Of course when you neglect your liver you know liver as they say you
“当然，当你忽视肝脏时，你知道人们常说，
will live till your liver will allow.
你活到你肝脏能允许的那刻。
Now this liver has to clean all the
现在这个肝脏不得不清理
poison from your body. It comes out as heat and is delivered to the blood stream. 。
所有从你的身体而来的毒素。它以热力的形式产生出来，并被输送到血液中。
But when this is neglected this poor liver doesn’t know
但当这一点被忽视，可怜的肝脏
how to function without the energy and all the heat is accumulated in the liver.
没有了能量不知道如何运转。所有的热力被积累在肝脏里面。
So a person suffers from liver trouble
因此一个有肝脏
and symptoms are he gets migraine,
问题的人会有这些症状，他会罹患偏头痛，
he cannot see the sun then also he gets very hot tempered,
他无法看阳光，也会脾气暴躁，
irritable, angry because there is so much of heat.
易被激怒，感到愤怒，因为有太多热力。
Then this heat passes; I was telling in Canberra most of the Bureaucrats
接着这热力传递开来。我说过在堪培拉（澳大利亚首都），大部分的官员们
have this problem
有这类问题。
because they plan too much and where do we land with
因为他们计划得太多，
that planning oh God all knows.
而我们要到哪里去实施这些计划呢。噢，天知道。
So then this heat passes upward and downward
接着这热力上行和下移，
so when it passes downward it gives you a very bad problem of terrible constipation
当它下移时，它带给你一种很坏的问题，可怕的便秘。
because the heat constitutes your intestine large intestines.
原因是热力堆积在你的肠子里，大肠里。
It also coagulates your kidneys by which you have kidney trouble
它也会让你的肾脏硬化，这样肾脏就出问题了，
you cannot pass your urine.
不能排出尿液。
Then you go on the dialysis and you are certified as really dead.
然后你要去做透析，接下来你被鉴定真正地死亡。
Because you cannot last longer.
因为你已时日无多。
So very expensive treatment but doctors do not tell you frankly
这是十分昂贵的治疗，可是医生们不会坦白地告诉你，
that oh, you are not going to live.
噢，你活不了啦。
Then this heat can pass upward and when it goes upward
这热力会上行，当它上行时，
it goes say to your right heart as shown there.
当它到达你的右心轮，如所示这里。
As a result of that you develop asthma.
你会患上哮喘。
Of course asthma is connected  also with the left side.
当然哮喘和左脉也有关系。
So when this triggering is done by the left side
因此左脉问题一旦被触发，你就会得
then you get this horrible disease called asthma.
哮喘这种可怕的疾病。
Then this heat can go upward and can ruin your throat.
接着这热力继续上行，会毁坏你的喉咙。
It can freeze your right arm.
It can freeze your right arm. 它会让你的右臂麻木，
It can make your left eye red and also your left ear deaf.
让你的左眼发红，还会让左耳聋掉。
But by chance if such a person is young and using too much physical
如果有这样一个年轻人过多使用身体
energy and mental energy as well as drinking a lot he can have a very
和精神能量，还酗酒，他会得致命的心脏病，
fatal heart attack very massive one and he may die in very early in age.
十分严重的那种，他有可能英年早逝。
You must know that all such attacks in
你要知道年轻人的所有这类心脏病
young age always are fatal.
发作起来总是致命的。
But when you see to the other side is that there
而在你的另一侧，
is a pancreas which is neglected
胰脏被忽略了，
as a result of the neglect of the pancreas
如果胰脏被忽视，
you develop a disease called diabetes.
结果是你会患上糖尿病。
Even the mothers who are extremely planning type and thinking
甚至如果母亲过度计划和思虑过多，
type give that disease to their children
她们会给孩子带来那种疾病，
and children are born with diabetes.
孩子出生就有先天糖尿病。
Then you have the third problem with the spleen.
然后你会有第三种和脾脏有关的问题。
This is the most dangerous one.
这是最为危险的一种。
Now a days as the life is we are all time bound
当今时代我们的生活很匆忙，
very particular about time.
总在赶时间。
As a result of that we have become extremely hectic.
结果我们变得极端繁忙。
Supposing if you sleep very late in a night
假如你晚上睡得很晚，
then you have to get up early in the morning somehow.
而你第二天早上不得不早起。
Somehow get into your clothes and run to the office.
胡乱穿好了衣服，然后要赶去办公室。
Don’t even take your breakfast; your wife will give you so on the way in
你连早饭都顾不上吃；你妻子会给你早餐，你在路上
the car you are eating your breakfast and then you read the newspaper.
在车里吃着早饭，然后开始读报纸。
You get a shock of your life because so many horrible things are happening.
你感到震惊，因为生活中有这么多可怕的事情发生。
Newspaper will never give something that is good or is doing well.
报纸从不报道一些好事或是做得好的事情，
But something that is gone wrong to give a sensational feeling.
而总是那些不对头的事情，来耸人听闻。
It’s just a sometimes horrible thing so early in the morning
有时候这真是可怕的事情，大清早的
if you read something that is horrible being a human being then you sometimes shocked.
如果你看到这些可怕的报道，作为一个人，时不时的被震惊。
Then you find there is a jam on the way and you
接着你发现路上交通堵塞，
get so upset and all your peace is disturbed.
你好沮丧，以致你的平和完全被破坏了。
Now this spleen is responsible for creating red blood corpuscles
现在，当你处于紧急状态时脾脏负责制造红血球。
when you are in emergency. You must have seen when you eat
你一定也知道当你吃着东西奔跑时，
your food and you run you get a pain here.
你这个地方会疼。
That’s because your spleen is trying to pump out new RBC’s.
那是因为你的脾脏正在试图泵出新的红血球。
Now to create that poor this spleen has to work very hard but it cannot
现在要制造更多，可怜的脾脏不得不很努力地工作，
understand the crazy hectic personality.
但它理解不了这疯狂忙乱的人性。
Every time it tries to cope with it.It goes crazy.
每次当它试图配合时，它也就疯狂了。
So such a spleen becomes crazy and ultimately leads
因此这个脾脏会变得疯狂，
some triggering on the left hand side; 最终这种情况触发了左边的问题；
最终这种情况触发了左边的问题；
you develop a horrible disease called as leukemia or blood cancer.
你便患上可怕的白血病或血癌。
also your intestinal problems, the pain in stomach and all that indigestion
肠胃问题，胃疼和所有那些消化系统问题，
all go hand in hand only because of the
也接踵而来，只因为
one centre only on right hand side. I have not even described the left side centre.
右边的一个能量中心。我甚至还没讲述左边的能量中心。
So if I describe all this the whole Materia Medica will be described.
如果我说完所有这些，整个药物学就给讲述完了。
It’s like that. So all the permutations and combinations of these centres
就像那样。所有这些中心的排列组合状况
give you physical problem then the left side gives you the mental problem.”
带给你身体方面的问题，而左边带给你精神方面的问题。”
Jung called the left side the collective subconscious.
荣格把左脉称做集体潜意识。
This side of our psyche is very complex and
我们内在的这一边十分复杂，
affects it can have on our physical wellbeing are devastating.
而且对身体健康方面可以有毁灭性的影响。
“Because as it has been hypothesized in Sahajayoga that there are 7 main plexuses
“因为正如霎哈嘉瑜伽所认定的那样，有7个主要的神经丛，
and their functioning is dependent upon the individuals psycho social behavior.
它们的功能状况决定了一个人的精神状况和社会行为。
This is advancement in the understanding of psychosomatic medicine and human physiology.
这是对身心医学和人类生理学理解方面的进步。
For the first time it is possible to find the links between the behavior and the disease.
人们第一次有可能找出行为和疾病的关系，
Because up till now it was only thought that stress
因为迄今为止，人们只知道
can cause a variety of diseases from diabetes, hypertension, asthma,
压力会导致多种疾病，如糖尿病、高血压、哮喘、
rheumatoid arthritis, etc. etc. cancer even. But it was not known
关节炎等等，甚至癌症。但是人们还不知道
why a particular individual will get a particular disease.”
为何一个人会得某种疾病。”
“ if you read disease in medical literature you find
“如果你在医学文献中看到关于疾病的描述，
you could say that it is psychological stress
你发现可以说是身心压力
which is responsible for increasing incidence of hypertension
导致了在大部分的西方国家、发展中国家以及发达国家中
in most of the western countries, developing countries as well as the developed countries
高血压病例的增多。
and we found by our first thesis you see on which work was done that
通过第一个论题所做的研究工作，我们发现
this could be a very important if a person practices sahajayoga
这可能十分重要，如果一个人练习霎哈嘉瑜伽，
this stress factor can be managed very nicely.
便可以很好地控制压力因素。
Because all the parameters you see for testing whether a person is in a
因为你们看无论一个人是在压力，
state of stress, tension or anxiety are
紧张或者焦虑状态，
in his relaxed strain who are done
所有测试参数都在他放松压力后的情况下测得，
and that we found that a person who do sahajayoga
我们发现一个人每天练习霎哈嘉瑜伽
only for 20 minutes a day you see in about 3-4 months time that
只需20分钟，大约3-4个月时间
there were changes in the blood,
在血液方面便有改进，
there were changes in heart,
心脏功能有改进，
there were changes in the lactrine cyclograph,
脑电图有变化，
there were changes in the muscle activity
在肌肉活动方面也有改变，
and the changes in the neurotransmitter.”
神经传导素也有改变。”
In the essential  hypertension group we have taken
“在原发性高血压组，我们选取的是
25 female patients of a similar age group
25名女性病人。
and socioeconomic status
她们的年龄和社会经济状况接近，
and out of these 15 patients voluntarily consented
其中15名病人自愿
to practice sahajayoga while 10 patients acted as controls
同意练习霎哈嘉瑜伽，而10名病人充当控制组角色。
and these patients initially both the groups were on drugs also.
这两组病人最初均需用药。
The initial blood pressure in the sahajayoga group was 169/109 mm of mercury
霎哈嘉瑜伽组开始的血压是169/109毫米汞柱，
and in the control group it was 166/111 mm of mercury
控制组是166/111毫米汞柱，
and as the study progressed for four months
研究进行了4个月，
we observed that many of the patients gradually could be taken
我们观察到许多病人逐渐
of the antihypertense of medication and at the end of 4 months all the
可以停用抗高血压药物，
patients in the sahajayoga group could be taken
而四个月的后期所有霎哈嘉瑜伽组病人可以
of the antihypertense of medication and the blood pressure
停用抗高血压药物，
had reached the level of 135/83 mm of mercury.
而且血压达到了135/83毫米汞柱水平。
While the control group blood pressure remained at 167/111 mm of mercury
而控制组血压还是在167/111毫米汞柱。
and this shows that it is possible to treat this condition
这表明，无需用药而通过霎哈嘉瑜伽练习
essential hypertension by practice of sahajayoga and without taking medicines.”
来治疗这种原发性高血压情况是有可能的。”
“ In my hospital I began to hold
“在我的医院，
use sahajayoga treatment on children and
我开始运用霎哈嘉瑜伽治疗儿童，
it so nice to see how it’s possible to resolve many questions, many problems
很高兴地看到它是如何解决了许多问题，许多病症。
corresponds child 7 yrs and he had big liver 1 cms
例如一个7岁的孩子，他肝脏肿大（11）厘米，
and lot of problems with joints and doctors could not make correctly diagnose.
关节有许多问题，医生不能做出正确的诊断。
But when I feel what chakras were affected.
但当我感觉到哪个轮穴受影响，
It was most swadhishthan, nabhi and agya
主要是腹轮，脐轮和额轮,
and after first my cleaning liver decreased 4 cm
我第一次为他做清理后，肝脏小了4cm，
and everyday more one cm and after 10 days he was absolutely well.
而且每天减小1cm, 过了10天后他完全康复了。
He had lot of neurological problem like teak like neurotic reaction
他有很多神经系统方面问题，像肌肉痉挛、焦虑反应，
and when he came back father couldn’t recognize him.
当他回家时，他父亲都认不出他了。
He sit quietly without problem. But of course
他安静地坐着没有任何问题。但是当然
you can’t introduce sahajayoga only in children mother has to be very very
你不能只给孩子们引入霎哈嘉瑜伽，母亲要参与，
with the children and the same and its usefull in other disease
要非常非常的和孩子一起并且同样的练习…在其他的疾病、
or for reference I worked in department of intensive care and recepation.
像其他的重症监护和门诊科室也起作用。
Sometimes I rise kundalini and severe attack of bronchial asthma disappear and many other cases .
有时我提升能量，然后严重的支气管哮喘消失了，也还有许多其他的案例。
Now I began to with one group of sahajayoga in hospital doctors,
现在我开始和一个医院的医生，护士和别的人组成的
nurses and other during about 2 months we began to start probably hospital
霎哈嘉瑜伽小组一起开展工作，大约有2个月时间,
and it gives effect.
它开始起效。
I am so happy that I stay in sahajayoga.
我很高兴留在霎哈嘉瑜伽。
and everyday thanks Shri Mataji. Jai Shri Mataji.”
每天都感谢锡吕玛塔吉。JAI SHRI MATAJI"
Western medicine has enhanced the quality of our life enormously
西方医学已经极大地提高了我们的生活质量，
and enables us to experience hillo to unknown heights in medical efficiency.
也使我们达到医学效率上的相当高度。
But in doing so it has lost sight of the whole.
但这样做的同时也失去了整体的视野。
By contrast medical doctrines such as traditional Chinese medicine
与此对比一些医学理论，
approach the human being as a whole personality the emotional stability,
例如传统中医是将人体看作一个整体。
mental attitude spiritual requirement and
情绪的稳定、精神的状态、灵性的需求
also sense morality are considered in a traditional chinese process of medical treatment.
和道德观念都在传统中医的医治过程中被加以考虑。
As a result traditional Chinese medicine treatment
从而，中医具有
has a subtlety which western medicine lacks.
西医所缺乏的精微性。
With this realization we have tried to
意识到这点，我们尝试
translate Chinese medicines into western culture and into western contexts
把中医药翻译引进西方文化和环境中。
but in doing so the foundation has largely been lost.
但这样做的时候，基础已经很大程度被丢失了。
The focus in western medicine remains set up on the element
西方医学着重点在于单个元素，
and not upon a whole person or his subtle relationship with the universe.
而不在于作为整体的人，或他和宇宙的精微关系上。
Like Jung’s anima and animus the yin and yang represents the
像荣格理论的(男性的)女性特征(anima)、(女性的)男性特征(animus)，
masculine or feminine or right or left side of our psyche.
阴和阳代表男性或女性 或我们内在的右脉和左脉；
The yang being masculine active right side and
阳是右边的男性活动，
yin being the feminine passive side.
而阴是女性被动的一边。
Viewed in a light of sahajayoga we can see
从霎哈嘉瑜伽的观点来看，我们可以看到
how this parallel is the subtle system.
这样的平行体如何组成精微系统。
In sahajayoga Tao refers to the balancing of right and left side.
在霎哈嘉瑜伽，“道”所指的是平衡右脉和左脉。
When this balance is maintained the healing energy is able to travel
当这个平衡得以维持的时候，一股疗愈的能量便可以
on the central channel to integrate and nourish all the energy centers
通行于中脉，整合并滋养所有的能量中心，
and ultimately keep us in harmony with the balance of nature.
最终让我们达到与自然的平衡和谐。
“As we have two sides in our system of
由于我们的自动神经系统有两脉，
autonomous nervous system left and right
左脉和右脉，
which we call as left and right sympathetic nervous system.
我们把它们称为左右交感神经系统。
The left side caters for our emotions, for our past, our desires.
左脉对应于我们的情绪，我们的过去，我们的愿望。
The right side caters for our action physical and mental.
右脉对应于我们身体和精神的活动。
If we indulge into one too much and go too far with it
如果我们过于沉溺其一，并偏离太多，
you develop an imbalance within yourself.
内在就会产生不平衡。
In the centre lies the third power which we call as parasympathetic nervous system.
在中脉存在着第三种力量，我们称它为副交感神经系统。
This is channel which is the central path of ascent.
这个通道是升进的中间道路。
When the kundalini rises through it, it brings you in the balance
当灵量通过它升起时，会带给你平衡，
because it rises in the centre of the system.
因为它从这个系统的中脉升上来。
So this is a minimum that happens that you develop your balance.”
所以，最起码会发生的是，你得到平衡。”
The ascent which is the awakening of this feminine energy coiled
通过唤醒在我们荐骨里面一个卷曲
and sleeping in our sacrum bone nourishes and revives the subtle system.
和沉睡的母性力量来达到的灵性上的升进，可以滋养和恢复我们的精微能量系统。
She is like the Mother Earth or our own Mother soothing,
她就像大地母亲或者我们的母亲，
nourishing and sustained the powers of gentle and strong.
给予我们舒缓，滋养和支持的力量。我们的这个力量既温和又强大。
She is the kundalini the very root of our existence.
她是灵量，我们存在的根本。
Within her lies the potential for us to become complete in knowledge of ourselves.
在她之内，储存着让我们可以完全了解我们自己的潜力。
“All right what I tried to show them that this is the left side this is the right side.
我所告诉的是，这是左脉，这是右脉。
This is the left sympathetic nervous system
这是左交感神经系统，
and same this is the right sympathetic nervous system
同样的这是右交感神经系统，
and really spinal cord looks like this and
还有脊椎看起来真的像这样，
inside here is the spinal cord which has the centres in it.
在这里面是脊椎，这些能量中心在脊椎里面。
The subtle centres.
精微的能量中心。
Now when you start using the energy of these
现在当你开始使用这些中心的能量，
centres say too much on the right and it starts moving more towards
例如右脉能量使用过度时，它开始更加偏移到右侧，
the right and there is a constriction and the power becomes less because
会出现收缩，而你的力量减弱了，
you are exhausted going more towards the right side.
因为过度偏向右脉你会精疲力尽。
Suddenly something happens that from left there is a jerk
突然会发生问题，左脉猛地一拉，
then the connection is completely broken.
接着与整体的联系完全被破坏了。
This is on its own.
它独立开来。
It starts working on its own that’s we say
它开始独立地工作。那就是我们说的，
that this has become malignant and no relationship with the whole
它变成了恶性的，并且和整体
to have the proportionate growth.
成比例的成长没有了关系。
So if the nose starts developing it can cover
所以当鼻子开始自顾发展，
your eyes and cover your mouth everything.
它会盖住你的眼睛，还会盖住你的嘴巴，以及所有的其他部分。
This is how a cancer is set in or any other disease
这就是癌症如何产生，或是任何其它疾病。
so many psychosomatic disease are nothing but somatic is from right side and when
那么多的身心疾病不是什么，而是先是从肉身，从右脉出现问题,
the psyche gives in then it becomes a psychosomatic.
当精神心理方面也参与进来，就形成身心疾病。
There are so many diseases which are more psychosomatic than the physical
有很多的疾病，它们更多属于身心病，而不仅是身体上的，
and these we call them as incurable can be easily cured by kundalini awakening
像这些被认为是不治之症，在灵量唤醒后，也可以很容易治愈。
because when kundalini passes through this she just integrates them for example
因为当灵量通过这里，就把它们整合起来，
she going like this then she goes into this integrates them.
例如她像这样走，接着她进入这里，整合它们。
Just like she strings them like pearls and so they
就像串珍珠一样，让它们
are brought round and also she nourishes that centre
恢复正常，她也滋养那能量中心，
that’s how people get cured automatically by themselves by their own power.”
人们就这样自动地被自己的力量治愈。”
Again if we look at traditional Indian medicine
再回来如果我们看看传统印度医学，
the purpose of Ayurvedic medicine was to integrate the mental, physical
阿育吠陀医学的目的是整合病人在精神，身体
and spiritual wellbeing of patient.
和灵性上的安康，
The identification of three points of reference bile,
它认为（人体的生理功能）分别为胆汁、
phlegm and wind corresponds in sahajayoga to the
粘液和风这三大因素，而在霎哈嘉瑜伽中
manifestation of right, left and central channels respectively.
各自对应为右脉，左脉和中脉。
“As you know that health is normally that is not diseased
“如你所知，健康不是处在病态，
but it is the state of complete mental, physical,
而是处在精神、身体、
emotional, spiritual and social wellbeing.
情绪、灵性和社会状态完全安康良好的状态。
Now this spiritual aspect of health has been missed in modern medicine.
现在关于灵性方面的安康在现代医学中已经被遗忘。
It is not known, taught or practiced in modern medicine.
在现代医学中，没有去了解、教授或实践这部分的知识。
This word kundalini does not find mention in the modern medical textbooks
灵量（昆达里尼）这个词在现代医学教科书中没有提及，
but it was mentioned in and may mentioned Indian medical textbooks
但在印度阿育吠陀医学教科书
of Ayurveda and many other religious textbooks religious scriptures.”
和许多其他宗教教科书、宗教名著中都有提到。”
“There is a subtle power which is all pervading of God’s love which
“有一个无所不在的上天浩爱的精微力量，
manifests all the thing like living work, all nourishment all balancing.
彰显在所有的事物中，在生活和工作中， 并带来所有的滋养和平衡。
It’s so balanced.
祂是那么的平衡。
If the pacific was slightly deeper than this; there would have been problems.
如果太平洋只是再深一点点，都会出问题了。
If Himalaya was say one and half times than what it is there would have been problems.
如果喜马拉雅山再高出1.5倍，那也有问题了。
So everything is so balanced in nature.”
所以自然界中的一切都是如此的平衡。”
"Which is the subtle energy all around us which organizes us and
“这是围绕在我们周围的精微能量，是祂组织我们并且
which nourishes us, does all the living work and above all it loves us”
滋养我们，是祂在做所有关乎生命的工作，而最重要的是祂爱我们。”
Sahajayoga takes us back to this original desire and in practice for future.
霎哈嘉瑜伽把我们带回到这个原初的愿望，并且为将来奠定基础。
In adressing of spiritual needs of the human being sahajayoga has
针对人类在灵性上的需求，霎哈嘉瑜伽
potential to bring balance back into west and back into western medicine.
有潜力可以把平衡带回西方社会与医学。
The essence of sahajayoga is not to cure people.
霎哈嘉瑜伽的精粹不在于治愈人们，
This is a side effect of the subtle system bring itself into balance
那只是精微能量系统恢复平衡后的副产品。
As its called sahajayoga enables us to discover our true selves
如它所说，霎哈嘉瑜伽使我们可以发现内在真正的自己、
the purpose of our being, the true meaning of why we are here.
我们生存的目的、及我们为何在此处的真正意义。
“The reason is you have to now become the spirit
“原因是你现在必须成为灵，
go beyond your physical, emotional, mental being and become the spirit.
超越你的身体、情绪与思维，成为灵。
Because spirit is the reflection of God all mighty
因为灵是至高无上的神的反映，
and spirit is the universal being within you.
灵是你内在的普遍存有。
When you become the spirit you become a universal being.”
当你成为灵你就成为一个普遍存有。”
www.sahajayoga.org www.sahajayoga.org.cn
www.sahajayoga.org www.sahajayoga.org.cn